capella.edu 2006-04-25

# Capella University - Legal, Regulatory and Accreditation Information

At Capella University, we believe that real, life-changing learning can only take place in an environment of challenge, engagement, academic excellence, and mutual respect including respect for each individual's privacy. This Online Privacy Policy describes our commitment to privacy and reflects the importance we place on earning and keeping your trust. 

**Table of Contents**

Scope Of This Policy  
Definitions  
Your Consent   
Your Choices   
This Privacy Policy May Change   
What Information Is Collected on this Site and How Is It Used?   
   Information You Knowingly and Voluntarily Provide   
   Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser  
   Information Collected By Placing a "Cookie" On Your Computer  
Use of Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies by Our Third-Party Ad Servers   
Does Capella Share My Personal Data?  
How Does Capella Protect My Personal Information?  
Does Capella Collect Personal Information From Children Through This Site?  
What About Other Sites That May Be Linked To This Site?  
Access to Personal Information  
Retention of Personal Information  
Governing Law  
Questions about this Policy or Our Data Practices  

**Scope Of This Policy.**

This Online Privacy Policy (this "Policy") describes our online information practices and some of the choices you can make about the ways we collect and use your personal information. 

Particular pages of this Site may contain notices providing more details about the information we collect on those particular pages. Certain portions of this Site may contain notices advising you that different policies and practices apply to the information collected through those particular portions of this Site, in which case those different policies and practices will supersede this Policy. These additional notices are referred to as "Privacy Notices" in this Policy. 

If you are a learner (or are applying to become a learner) at Capella, your personal information may also be protected under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act ("FERPA"). The provisions of FERPA supercede and govern over any contrary provisions in this Policy. Learn more about FERPA and Capella's FERPA Compliance Program.

This Policy does not cover any employees, faculty, contractors, consultants, or agents of Capella. 

**Definitions**

As used in this Policy, the term "personal information" means information that identifies you personally, alone or in combination with other information available to us; the term "Site" means our website at www.capella.edu; and the terms "Capella," "we," "us," and "our" refer to Capella University, Inc. 

**Your Consent**

By using this Site, you are consenting to the collection, use, and transfer of your personal information as described in this Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you). If you do not consent to the collection, use and transfer of your personal information as described in this Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you), you may not use this Site. 

**Your Choices**

We respect your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use, and share your personal information. This Policy describes some of your choices. In most cases, however, we will ask you to indicate your choices at the time and on the page where you provide your personal information. 

**This Privacy Policy May Change**

Capella reserves the right to update or modify this Policy and any Privacy Notice, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of the Policy or Privacy Notice on this Site. If we modify this Policy or any Privacy Notice, the modifications will only apply to the personal information we collect after we have posted the revised Policy or Privacy Notice on this Site. 

Your use of this Site following any such change constitutes your agreement that all information collected from or about you after the revised Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Policy. You may access the current version of this Policy at any time by clicking on the link marked "Privacy" at the bottom of each page of the public areas of this Site. For your convenience, when we modify this Policy we will post a notice informing users of the change for thirty days on the "Contact Us" page of this Site. 

This Policy was last revised on September 22, 2005 and is effective as of that date. 

**What Information Is Collected on this Site and How Is It Used?**

When you access and use this Site, there are three ways we may collect information about you: 

**_1._** ** _Information You Knowingly and Voluntarily Provide._**

Capella collects the information you knowingly and voluntarily provide when you use this Site, for example, the information you provide when you request information or a University Guide, complete a survey, or e-mail us with questions or feedback. In many cases, this information will identify you personally. 

Capella uses the personal information you volunteer through this Site to provide the information, services and products you request. For example, we use the information you provide when you request a University Guide to deliver the University Guide to you, and we use your e-mail address to respond to your comments or questions. 

We may also use your contact information to follow up with you after you have expressed an interest in our programs. For example, after we send you our University Guide, we may telephone you to see if you have questions. We respect your privacy, however. If your telephone number is on a "Do Not Call" list, we will send you an e-mail requesting permission to call you and will only do so with your consent. 

Unless you have "opted-out," we will add your contact information to our mailing lists and from time to time we will send you newsletters or updates, special offers, or other information about programs, services and products we believe would be of interest to you. You may "opt out" of receiving this information from us at any time by calling us at 1-888-CAPELLA (1-888-227-3552) option 3. If you are receiving e-mail from us and wish to unsubscribe, please click on the unsubscribe link provided in the e-mail you receive from us. 

If we provide promotional information or materials to you by e-mail, we will include a link to our "opt-out" page in every e-mail. 

Finally, we may study the personal information collected through this Site to improve our programs and services, to improve the content, functionality, navigation, and usability of this Site; to better understand the needs and interests of learners, alumni, and the other constituencies we serve; and to better market our programs, services, and products. We may also remove all the personally identifiable information and use the rest for historical, statistical, or scientific purposes. 

**_2\. Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser_**

Capella collects information that is sent to us automatically by your Web browser. This information typically includes the IP address of your Internet service provider, the name of your operating system (such as Windows® or Macintosh®), and the name and version of your browser (such as Netscape® or Internet Explorer®). The information we receive depends on the settings on your Web browser. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings. 

The information provided by your browser does not identify you personally. Unless you access this Site through an e-mail we have sent you or have created a "user identity" by creating an account during one of your visits, this information will not be linked to information that identifies you personally. We use this information to create statistics that help us improve our Site and make it more compatible with the technology used by our visitors. 

**_3\. Information Collected By Placing a "Cookie" On Your Computer_**

Capella may obtain information about you by installing a cookie on your computer's hard drive. A cookie is a piece of Web code that is used primarily for one or more of the following: analysis of Web site traffic and user behavior, application functionality, and data storage. We use two types of cookies: "session cookies" and "persistent cookies." 

We use "session cookies" to assign a randomly-generated unique identification number to your computer. A session cookie does not identify you personally, and expires (i.e., is automatically deleted from your computer) after you close your browser. We use session cookies to collect statistical information about the ways visitors use our site — which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. We analyze this information (known as "clickstream data") to better understand our visitors' interests and needs and to improve the content and functionality of our sites. We do not link this information with any information that identifies you personally. 

We use "persistent cookies" (cookies that do not expire when you close your browser) for several purposes. Like session cookies, they are used to assign a unique identifier to your computer, but because they are persistent, they permit us to recognize your computer each time you use it to access the Site. By using persistent cookies, we can collect and analyze clickstream data from more than one visit to the Site. Cookies are also used to store information you have previously provided such as your user ID or shipping address that can be displayed back to you automatically each time you visit the Site. Persistent cookies remain on your computer until you delete them or until they expire. Expiration durations vary and are set by Capella. 

Finally, both types of cookies (persistent and session) are occasionally used to facilitate the proper functioning of our applications and features of the Site. 

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. Although you are not required to accept cookies when you visit this Site, you may be unable to use all of the functionality of the Site if your browser rejects our cookies. 

**Use of Cookies, Web Beacons, and Similar Technologies by Our Third-Party Ad Servers**

Capella uses reputable third-party advertising companies to present ("serve") ads on our behalf. These third-party ad servers may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to help present and better target our advertisements, to measure the effectiveness of our advertisements, or to customize the content of the advertisements presented to you. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer's browser that can be used to help recognize you as someone who may be interested in online learning. Web beacons are small pieces of code placed on Web pages that can be used, among other things, to deliver a cookie to the browser of a computer accessing that page. [More information about our third-party ad servers, the technologies they use, and how you can disable or "opt-out" from receiving their cookies. ](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy/process/)

Sometimes Capella uses third party advertising companies to help us with our e-mail marketing campaigns. These third-party advertising companies may include cookies in the e-mails they send on our behalf. These cookies do not identify you personally. They do not track your use of the Internet or cause pop-up ads to appear. They are used to help the Web sites you visit recognize you as someone with an interest in online education and to customize the content of the ads presented to you. Your browser can not screen out cookies that are sent by e-mail, but you can easily disable these cookies by visiting the ad server's Web site and following the instructions posted there. [View links to our ad server's Web sites.](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy/blocking)

The use of cookies, web beacons and similar technologies by these third party advertising companies is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our privacy policy.

**Does Capella Share My Personal Data?**

Capella may share personal information collected through this Site with companies and organizations who perform certain functions on our behalf, for example, companies that provide support services to us or that help us market our products and services (such as third-party advertising companies and colleges with whom we have referral relationships). These third parties are required by contract to use the personal information we share with them only to perform services on our behalf and to treat your personal information as strictly confidential. To learn which third-party service providers we use, please contact us at 612-977-5662 **.** [Learn more about the ways our third-party advertising companies use cookies and other technologies to increase the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy/controlling/).

There are other limited circumstances in which Capella may share or transfer the personal information in our databases to unrelated third parties. For example, we may provide personal information to a third party when we believe it is necessary to comply with U.S. Department of Education reporting requirements or the reporting requirements of accrediting bodies; to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to comply with a court order or subpoena; to comply with a legal requirement; to enforce a contract; to protect the rights, property, or safety of Capella, our users or others; to protect your vital interests; or in connection with a corporate sale, purchase, merger, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or similar event. In particular, we exchange personal information in our databases with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction purposes. When we disclose information under these or similar circumstances, we will take appropriate steps to protect the confidentiality of your personal information. 

**How Does Capella Protect Personal Information?**

Although Capella cannot guarantee against any loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration or destruction of personal information, we take measures to prevent such occurrences. Our servers and databases are protected by firewalls and passwords. In addition, we use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software to encrypt data as it travels between your computer and our servers. When you see a solid key or a locked padlock icon at the lower portion of your browser window, this indicates that your transmission will be protected by SSL technology. 

**Does Capella Collect Personal Information From Children Through This Site?**

Capella does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen through this Site. If you are under thirteen, please do not give us any information that identifies you personally. If you have reason to believe that your child has provided personal information to Capella through this Site, please contact us, and we will use reasonable efforts to delete that information from our databases. 

**What About Other Sites That May Be Linked To This Site?**

This Site contains links to other Web sites operated by Capella. This Site also contains links to Web sites that are owned and operated by unrelated third parties. For example, this Site contains links to a wide spectrum of resources that may be useful to Learners. In addition, this Site contains links to Web sites operated by third parties who provide services to Capella. For example, Capella uses a third-party service provider to process credit card transactions. If you wish to make a payment by credit card, we will ask you to click on a link that will take you to our service provider's Web sites. 

This Privacy Statement applies only to personal information collected through this Site. It does not apply to personal information collected on any other Web sites operated by Capella, nor to personal information collected on our service providers' or other third-party Web sites. When you access other Web sites through a link on this Site, please take a few minutes to review the terms of use and privacy statement posted on each Web site you visit. 

**Access to Personal Information**

If you have created a Capella account and would like to review, correct, and update the personal information you have provide to us, please [edit this form](https://www.capella.edu/Portal/Learner/ContactInfo.aspx) or call us at 1-888-CAPELLA (1-888-227-3552) option 2. 

If you have not created an account, but would like to review, correct, and update the personal information you have provided to us through this Site, please contact us by filling out a request  or telephone us at 1-888-CAPELLA (1-888-227-3552) option 3\. 

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request. 

**Retention of Personal Information**

Capella retains the personal information collected on this Site as long as necessary to provide the services, products, and information you request or as permitted by applicable law. 

Our servers are located in the United States. While it is in our possession, your personal information will generally be stored in Capella databases or databases maintained by our service providers. Most, if not all, of these databases are stored on servers and storage devices located in the United States. United States data protection laws may not provide as much protection as the data protection laws in force in some other countries. If you are located in a country outside the United States, by using this Site you consent to the transfer of your personal information to the United States.

**Governing Law**

Capella University is a United States corporation. The servers that support this Site are located in the United States of America. This Policy shall be governed under the laws of the State of Minnesota, United States of America without regard to its conflicts of law provisions. 

**Questions about this Policy or our Data Practices**

If you have questions or concerns about this Policy or any Privacy Notice, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail at:

**Capella University**  
ATTN: Privacy Policy Manager  
225 South Sixth Street  
Minneapolis, MN 55402  
E-mail: [Onlinegroup@capella.edu](mailto:%22onlinegroup@capella.edu%22)
